23. Which of the following describes Information Technology (IT) Governance?
Informs decisions about IT investments, projects, and application portfolios
Digitizes information so that Data Governance can take place
Communicates Data Governance information to stakeholders
Procures data in a way that is aligned with ethical principles and responsibilities
Analyzes management of data as a strategic asset
0

25. Data is important to organizations in all but one of the following ways:
Organizations need data to conduct interactions with customers and constituents
Organizations need data to make decisions
Organizations need data for daily operations
Organizations sell data to third-parties
Organizations get value from data analytics
3

41. What are the two types of Data Integration processes involved in Data Warehousing?
Historical Loads, Ongoing Loads
Statistical Update, Historical Loads
Historical Update, Statistical Update
Historical Update, Ongoing Loads
Historical Loads, Ongoing Update
4

44. In past decades, information such as names and addresses might not have been considered data. Why has that changed?
These forms of information can now be analyzed to make business decisions
These forms of information can now can be stored digitally
These forms of information are now available online
These forms of information can be used for Data Science
These forms of information can be stored by the organization because of improvements in data encryption
0

11. Data created while operational processes are in progress is referred to as...
Resource information
Business event information
Category information
Detail transaction information
Detail resource information
1

31. What kind of software helps transform pick lists and controlled vocabularies into pick lists searchable from the home page?
Term Management
Software Management
Transformation Management
Content Management
Home Page Software
3

28. Which of the following is not necessary to realize Data Governance programs?
Develop policies and procedures
Cultivate data stewardship practices at multiple levels within the organization
Engage in organizational change management efforts
Engage in behaviors necessary to manage data as an asset
Communicate updated policies and procedures to external stakeholders
4

7. The first activity to be completed in the implementation of Data Governance is...
Perform readiness assessment
Perform discovery and business alignment
Define Data Governance for the organization
Develop organizational touchpoints
Develop Data Governance strategy
2

45. Which of the following is not a factor that determines the ability of an organization to adopt Data Architecture
practices?
Level of acceptance of formal data governance
Ability to holistically consider the enterprise and not focus on project delivery and IT
Cultural receptivity to an architectural approach
Organizational recognition of data as a business asset
Ability to put proper structures in place for the implementation of Data Architecture practices
4

36. What is the goal of Data Architecture?
To bridge the gap between business strategy and execution
To help organize a business strategy
For ease of data management
To structure and organize data
To facilitate smooth execution
0

49. What are the essential characteristics of high-quality data definitions?
Concreteness, Accuracy, Succinctness
Clarity, Accuracy, Succinctness
Clarity, Completeness, Succinctness
Clarity, Accuracy, Completeness
Clarity, Completeness, Concreteness
3

21. Why must all systems handling messages or data packets be able to manage the order of execution of those processes?
To preserve consistency and continuity
To ensure a good view
To make it durable
To ensure clarity of words
To make it complete
0

37. How does Data Modelling and Design help an organization complete initiatives?
Data Modelling depicts data visually
Data Modelling quickens the success of broad-scoped initiatives
Data Modelling confirms and documents understanding of different perspectives
Data Modelling increases the opportunity for future initiatives
Data Modelling visually presents Metadata
2

5. More than _______ of the documents created today are electronic.
60%
75%
80%
90%
98%
3

24. Big Data encompasses...
Speed, Accuracy, Quantity
Volume, Accuracy, Speed
Volume, Variety, Speed
Variety, Uniqueness, Volume
Uniqueness, Speed, Variety
2

30. What is the importance of Data Lineage Analysis to Data Flow?
It depicts how data moves through business processes and systems in the data flow
It explains the state of data at a given point in the data flow
It explains the direction of processes and systems in the data flow
It is a type of data lineage documentation
It shows the direction of data in a data flow
1

10. Data Management principles include all but one of the following?
It takes planning to manage data
Data Management requires an enterprise perspective
Data Management must drive information technology decisions
Different types of data have different lifecycle characteristics
Data Management must be done by experts
4

14. What does the acronym CIF refer to?
Corporate Information Factory
Company Information Factory
Company Information Facts
Corporate Information Facts
Corporate Intergroup Factory
0

33. Master & Reference Data Management are forms of which of the following?
Data Integration
Data Security
Data Warehousing
Dataset Procurement
Dataset Valuation
0

13. Basic data profiling involves analysis of the following except:
Data values and how closely they correspond to a defined set of valid values
Data format as defined in the data structures and inferred from the actual data
Correct data flow throughout the organization
Data population, including the levels of null, blank, and default records
Relationships to other datasets
2

3. Early Big Data was characterized by _______ V's but the number of V's has been expanded to _____
3, 5
2, 6
2, 5
3, 7
3, 6
4

4. What is the purpose of a Data Flow Design diagram?
Shows the movement of data
Shows how data moves through business processes and systems
Shows the data lifecycle
Shows how queries can be executed
Helps stakeholders understand data better
1

32. Control of contracts dealing with data, such as cloud storage, external data purchase, sales of data as a product, and outsourcing data operations - describes which driver of Data Governance?
Vendor management
General risk management
Data Quality improvement
Metadata Management
Data Privacy
0

19. Which data model pattern can be used to construct self-referencing hierarchies?
Integration Patterns
Accumulation Pattern
Construction Pattern
Assembly Pattern
Elementary Pattern
4

2. What is the end goal of Data Modelling?
Providing for the understanding organizational data
Creating a database
Assigning the correct data types
Implementing broadly scoped initiatives
Laying the groundwork for Master Data Management
0

16. Two systems that are tightly coupled are characterized by what kind of interface?
Asynchronous
Integration
Coupling
Synchronous
Overlapping
3

39. A thesaurus is a type of controlled vocabulary used for what purpose?
Content Management
Content Generation
Content Retrieval
Content Data
Content Reference
2

35. What is the name for an authoritative system where data is created, captured, and/or maintained through a defined set of rules and expectations?
A system of documents
A system of record
A system of data
A system of files
A system of reference
1

43. Which of the following is one of the ethical principles for data as adapted from the Belmont Principles?
Honesty
Transparency
Integrity
Respect for persons
Fairness
3

9. Master Data Management is...
Obstructive
Frustrating
Challenging
Disorganized
Oriented
2

34. The Strong-Wang framework describes ______ dimensions across ______ general categories of data quality.
4, 15
15, 4
5, 14
14, 5
15, 5
1

26. The understanding of data in terms of economic value is referred to as...
Data asset estimation
Data asset valuation
Economics of data asset
Customer data value
Customer data market value
1

12. What is the importance of Data Governance in Data Management?
It simplifies the understanding of data for easy implementation of Data Models
It governs the value enhancement process
It supports the categorization of data
It educates key stakeholders on how to make better data decisions
It governs how decisions are made about data and how people and processes are expected to behave in relation to data
4

22. What is accuracy?
Ensuring that no entity exists more than once within the dataset
Ensuring that data values are consistently represented within a dataset and between datasets and that that data values are consistently associated across datasets
Ensuring that required data is present
Ensuring data correctly represents 'real-life' entities
Refers to several characteristics of data
3

6. The implementation of a Data Warehouse should follow these guiding principles, except:
Think and design globally, act and build locally
Ensure business analysts are involved in decision support activities across the enterprise
Promote collaboration
One size does not fit all
Promote transparency and self-service access to data
1

18. Which among the following can be described as goals of a Master and Reference Data Management program?
Identification and restoration of improperly merged data
Enterprise-wide distribution of trusted data
Determine which sources will provide a comprehensive look at Master Data entities
Analyze root causes of issues. 
Identify the latency between the source system and the consumption system
Matching and linking new records from a starting point. 
Provide information that may not be readily available during record creation
To make sure that the enterprise has complete, current and authoritative master and reference data for their organizational processes.
To provide master and reference data across all functions and applications of the enterprise.
To reduce the cost and complexity of data usage through common data models.
7,8,9

1. What is the importance of Enterprise Data Architecture?
It shows the flow of data
It explains the elements that are important to the organization
It gives a pictorial representation of business elements
It defines standard terms and designs for the elements that are important to the organization
It represents a collection of Enterprise Data Models
3

50. Data Science used to be called which of the following?
Applied Data
Data Application
Applied Statistics
Data Analysis
Statistics Application
2

48. Which of the following is NOT a principle guiding online data practices in the United States?
Ownership of data
Identity
The right to be forgotten
Right to sue against the proliferation of false personal information online
Freedom of speech online
3

38. A Services Based Architecture has these three main components:
Batch Layer, Data Layer, Serving Layer
Batch Layer, Speed Layer, Serving Layer
Statistics Layer, Data Layer, Serving Layer
Serving Layer, Speed Layer, Statistics Layer
Batch Layer, Speed Layer, Data Layer
1

40. What is the name for the index that points to Master Data in the various systems of record?
Record
Table of Contents
Appendix
Registry
Database
3

42. In the context of Information Technology, which of the following defines data?
Information stored on computers
Information stored on SD cards
Information stored in a Data Warehouse or Operational Data Store
Information in a data center or in the cloud
Information stored in digital form
4

17. What is e-discovery?
The ability of an organization to effectively respond to litigation
The process of finding electronic records that might serve as evidence in a legal action
Planning, implementation, and control activities for data lifecycle management
Website utilized to manage records and published information
Modern approach to records management
1

29. High-quality data is a means to...
Organizational success
Decreased customer service calls
Means unto itself
Make quicker decisions
Means to an end
0

47. The Shewhart / Deming cycle is also known as...
Database cycle
Data Management
Content Generation
Redman Cycle
Plan-do-check-act
4

27. What is the data source of a Data Warehouse?
Master Data
Conformed dimension contents from separate repositories
Data Structures based on performance
Historical, atomized data
Staging area
1

20. Why is Data Architecture important to Data Management?
Provides for an understanding of an organization's data at different levels of abstraction
Creates data about data
Breaks down data systems into easily comprehensible units
Create structured representations of data
Supports the utilization of data to make sound decisions
0

15. Which of the following is NOT a function of Data Architects?
Facilitate alignment between Business and IT
Act as agents for change, transformation, and agility
Manage complex data and information delivery throughout the enterprise
Translate business needs into data and system requirements so processes will have their required data
Strategize on how to procure data that meets the needs of the organization
4

46. Thomas Redman defines a data item as...
Representative triple
Representative double
Representable triple
Representable double
Representing triple
2

51. Which of the following is used to exchange information within the Semantic Web?
Taxonomy
Thesaurus
Data Model
Syntax
Ontology
4



-------------------------------------------

{"question": "Which of the following describes Information Technology (IT) Governance?",
"answers": ["Informs decisions about IT investments, projects, and application portfolios",
 "Digitizes information so that Data Governance can take place",
 "Communicates Data Governance information to stakeholders",
 "Procures data in a way that is aligned with ethical principles and responsibilities",
 "Analyzes management of data as a strategic asset"],
"valid": [0]},

{"question": "Data is important to organizations in all but one of the following ways:",
"answers": ["Organizations need data to conduct interactions with customers and constituents",
 "Organizations need data to make decisions",
 "Organizations need data for daily operations",
 "Organizations sell data to third-parties",
 "Organizations get value from data analytics"],
"valid": [3]},

{"question": "What are the two types of Data Integration processes involved in Data Warehousing?",
"answers": ["Historical Loads, Ongoing Loads",
 "Statistical Update, Historical Loads",
 "Historical Update, Statistical Update",
 "Historical Update, Ongoing Loads",
 "Historical Loads, Ongoing Update"],
"valid": [4]},

{"question": "In past decades, information such as names and addresses might not have been considered data. Why has that changed?",
"answers": ["These forms of information can now be analyzed to make business decisions",
 "These forms of information can now can be stored digitally",
 "These forms of information are now available online",
 "These forms of information can be used for Data Science",
 "These forms of information can be stored by the organization because of improvements in data encryption"],
"valid": [0]},

{"question": "Data created while operational processes are in progress is referred to as...",
"answers": ["Resource information",
 "Business event information",
 "Category information",
 "Detail transaction information",
 "Detail resource information"],
"valid": [1]},

{"question": "What kind of software helps transform pick lists and controlled vocabularies into pick lists searchable from the home page?",
"answers": ["Term Management",
 "Software Management",
 "Transformation Management",
 "Content Management",
 "Home Page Software"],
"valid": [3]},

{"question": "Which of the following is not necessary to realize Data Governance programs?",
"answers": ["Develop policies and procedures",
 "Cultivate data stewardship practices at multiple levels within the organization",
 "Engage in organizational change management efforts",
 "Engage in behaviors necessary to manage data as an asset",
 "Communicate updated policies and procedures to external stakeholders"],
"valid": [4]},

{"question": "The first activity to be completed in the implementation of Data Governance is...",
"answers": ["Perform readiness assessment",
 "Perform discovery and business alignment",
 "Define Data Governance for the organization",
 "Develop organizational touchpoints",
 "Develop Data Governance strategy"],
"valid": [2]},

{"question": "Which of the following is not a factor that determines the ability of an organization to adopt Data Architecture",
"answers": ["practices?",
 "Level of acceptance of formal data governance",
 "Ability to holistically consider the enterprise and not focus on project delivery and IT",
 "Cultural receptivity to an architectural approach",
 "Organizational recognition of data as a business asset",
 "Ability to put proper structures in place for the implementation of Data Architecture practices"],
"valid": [4]},

{"question": "What is the goal of Data Architecture?",
"answers": ["To bridge the gap between business strategy and execution",
 "To help organize a business strategy",
 "For ease of data management",
 "To structure and organize data",
 "To facilitate smooth execution"],
"valid": [0]},

{"question": "What are the essential characteristics of high-quality data definitions?",
"answers": ["Concreteness, Accuracy, Succinctness",
 "Clarity, Accuracy, Succinctness",
 "Clarity, Completeness, Succinctness",
 "Clarity, Accuracy, Completeness",
 "Clarity, Completeness, Concreteness"],
"valid": [3]},

{"question": "Why must all systems handling messages or data packets be able to manage the order of execution of those processes?",
"answers": ["To preserve consistency and continuity",
 "To ensure a good view",
 "To make it durable",
 "To ensure clarity of words",
 "To make it complete"],
"valid": [0]},

{"question": "How does Data Modelling and Design help an organization complete initiatives?",
"answers": ["Data Modelling depicts data visually",
 "Data Modelling quickens the success of broad-scoped initiatives",
 "Data Modelling confirms and documents understanding of different perspectives",
 "Data Modelling increases the opportunity for future initiatives",
 "Data Modelling visually presents Metadata"],
"valid": [2]},

{"question": "More than _______ of the documents created today are electronic.",
"answers": ["60%",
 "75%",
 "80%",
 "90%",
 "98%"],
"valid": [3]},

{"question": "Big Data encompasses...",
"answers": ["Speed, Accuracy, Quantity",
 "Volume, Accuracy, Speed",
 "Volume, Variety, Speed",
 "Variety, Uniqueness, Volume",
 "Uniqueness, Speed, Variety"],
"valid": [2]},

{"question": "What is the importance of Data Lineage Analysis to Data Flow?",
"answers": ["It depicts how data moves through business processes and systems in the data flow",
 "It explains the state of data at a given point in the data flow",
 "It explains the direction of processes and systems in the data flow",
 "It is a type of data lineage documentation",
 "It shows the direction of data in a data flow"],
"valid": [1]},

{"question": "Data Management principles include all but one of the following?",
"answers": ["It takes planning to manage data",
 "Data Management requires an enterprise perspective",
 "Data Management must drive information technology decisions",
 "Different types of data have different lifecycle characteristics",
 "Data Management must be done by experts"],
"valid": [4]},

{"question": "What does the acronym CIF refer to?",
"answers": ["Corporate Information Factory",
 "Company Information Factory",
 "Company Information Facts",
 "Corporate Information Facts",
 "Corporate Intergroup Factory"],
"valid": [0]},

{"question": "Master & Reference Data Management are forms of which of the following?",
"answers": ["Data Integration",
 "Data Security",
 "Data Warehousing",
 "Dataset Procurement",
 "Dataset Valuation"],
"valid": [0]},

{"question": "Basic data profiling involves analysis of the following except:",
"answers": ["Data values and how closely they correspond to a defined set of valid values",
 "Data format as defined in the data structures and inferred from the actual data",
 "Correct data flow throughout the organization",
 "Data population, including the levels of null, blank, and default records",
 "Relationships to other datasets"],
"valid": [2]},

{"question": "Early Big Data was characterized by _______ V's but the number of V's has been expanded to _____",
"answers": ["3 and 5",
 "2 and 6",
 "2 and 5",
 "3 and 7",
 "3 and 6"],
"valid": [4]},

{"question": "What is the purpose of a Data Flow Design diagram?",
"answers": ["Shows the movement of data",
 "Shows how data moves through business processes and systems",
 "Shows the data lifecycle",
 "Shows how queries can be executed",
 "Helps stakeholders understand data better"],
"valid": [1]},

{"question": "Control of contracts dealing with data, such as cloud storage, external data purchase, sales of data as a product, and outsourcing data operations - describes which driver of Data Governance?",
"answers": ["Vendor management",
 "General risk management",
 "Data Quality improvement",
 "Metadata Management",
 "Data Privacy"],
"valid": [0]},

{"question": "Which data model pattern can be used to construct self-referencing hierarchies?",
"answers": ["Integration Patterns",
 "Accumulation Pattern",
 "Construction Pattern",
 "Assembly Pattern",
 "Elementary Pattern"],
"valid": [4]},

{"question": "What is the end goal of Data Modelling?",
"answers": ["Providing for the understanding organizational data",
 "Creating a database",
 "Assigning the correct data types",
 "Implementing broadly scoped initiatives",
 "Laying the groundwork for Master Data Management"],
"valid": [0]},

{"question": "Two systems that are tightly coupled are characterized by what kind of interface?",
"answers": ["Asynchronous",
 "Integration",
 "Coupling",
 "Synchronous",
 "Overlapping"],
"valid": [3]},

{"question": "A thesaurus is a type of controlled vocabulary used for what purpose?",
"answers": ["Content Management",
 "Content Generation",
 "Content Retrieval",
 "Content Data",
 "Content Reference"],
"valid": [2]},

{"question": "What is the name for an authoritative system where data is created, captured, and/or maintained through a defined set of rules and expectations?",
"answers": ["A system of documents",
 "A system of record",
 "A system of data",
 "A system of files",
 "A system of reference"],
"valid": [1]},

{"question": "Which of the following is one of the ethical principles for data as adapted from the Belmont Principles?",
"answers": ["Honesty",
 "Transparency",
 "Integrity",
 "Respect for persons",
 "Fairness"],
"valid": [3]},

{"question": "Master Data Management is...",
"answers": ["Obstructive",
 "Frustrating",
 "Challenging",
 "Disorganized",
 "Oriented"],
"valid": [2]},

{"question": "The Strong-Wang framework describes ______ dimensions across ______ general categories of data quality.",
"answers": ["4 and 15",
 "15 and 4",
 "5 and 14",
 "14 and 5",
 "15 and 5"],
"valid": [1]},

{"question": "The understanding of data in terms of economic value is referred to as...",
"answers": ["Data asset estimation",
 "Data asset valuation",
 "Economics of data asset",
 "Customer data value",
 "Customer data market value"],
"valid": [1]},

{"question": "What is the importance of Data Governance in Data Management?",
"answers": ["It simplifies the understanding of data for easy implementation of Data Models",
 "It governs the value enhancement process",
 "It supports the categorization of data",
 "It educates key stakeholders on how to make better data decisions",
 "It governs how decisions are made about data and how people and processes are expected to behave in relation to data"],
"valid": [4]},

{"question": "What is accuracy?",
"answers": ["Ensuring that no entity exists more than once within the dataset",
 "Ensuring that data values are consistently represented within a dataset and between datasets and that that data values are consistently associated across datasets",
 "Ensuring that required data is present",
 "Ensuring data correctly represents 'real-life' entities",
 "Refers to several characteristics of data"],
"valid": [3]},

{"question": "The implementation of a Data Warehouse should follow these guiding principles, except:",
"answers": ["Think and design globally, act and build locally",
 "Ensure business analysts are involved in decision support activities across the enterprise",
 "Promote collaboration",
 "One size does not fit all",
 "Promote transparency and self-service access to data"],
"valid": [1]},

{"question": "Which among the following can be described as goals of a Master and Reference Data Management program?",
"answers": ["Identification and restoration of improperly merged data",
 "Enterprise-wide distribution of trusted data",
 "Determine which sources will provide a comprehensive look at Master Data entities",
 "Analyze root causes of issues. ",
 "Identify the latency between the source system and the consumption system",
 "Matching and linking new records from a starting point. ",
 "Provide information that may not be readily available during record creation",
 "To make sure that the enterprise has complete, current and authoritative master and reference data for their organizational processes.",
 "To provide master and reference data across all functions and applications of the enterprise.",
 "To reduce the cost and complexity of data usage through common data models.",
"valid": [7,8,9]},

{"question": "What is the importance of Enterprise Data Architecture?",
"answers": ["It shows the flow of data",
 "It explains the elements that are important to the organization",
 "It gives a pictorial representation of business elements",
 "It defines standard terms and designs for the elements that are important to the organization",
 "It represents a collection of Enterprise Data Models"],
"valid": [3]},

{"question": "Data Science used to be called which of the following?",
"answers": ["Applied Data",
 "Data Application",
 "Applied Statistics",
 "Data Analysis",
 "Statistics Application"],
"valid": [2]},

{"question": "Which of the following is NOT a principle guiding online data practices in the United States?",
"answers": ["Ownership of data",
 "Identity",
 "The right to be forgotten",
 "Right to sue against the proliferation of false personal information online",
 "Freedom of speech online"],
"valid": [3]},

{"question": "A Services Based Architecture has these three main components:",
"answers": ["Batch Layer, Data Layer, Serving Layer",
 "Batch Layer, Speed Layer, Serving Layer",
 "Statistics Layer, Data Layer, Serving Layer",
 "Serving Layer, Speed Layer, Statistics Layer",
 "Batch Layer, Speed Layer, Data Layer"],
"valid": [1]},

{"question": "What is the name for the index that points to Master Data in the various systems of record?",
"answers": ["Record",
 "Table of Contents",
 "Appendix",
 "Registry",
 "Database"],
"valid": [3]},

{"question": "In the context of Information Technology, which of the following defines data?",
"answers": ["Information stored on computers",
 "Information stored on SD cards",
 "Information stored in a Data Warehouse or Operational Data Store",
 "Information in a data center or in the cloud",
 "Information stored in digital form"],
"valid": [4]},

{"question": "What is e-discovery?",
"answers": ["The ability of an organization to effectively respond to litigation",
 "The process of finding electronic records that might serve as evidence in a legal action",
 "Planning, implementation, and control activities for data lifecycle management",
 "Website utilized to manage records and published information",
 "Modern approach to records management"],
"valid": [1]},

{"question": "High-quality data is a means to...",
"answers": ["Organizational success",
 "Decreased customer service calls",
 "Means unto itself",
 "Make quicker decisions",
 "Means to an end"],
"valid": [0]},

{"question": "The Shewhart / Deming cycle is also known as...",
"answers": ["Database cycle",
 "Data Management",
 "Content Generation",
 "Redman Cycle",
 "Plan-do-check-act"],
"valid": [4]},

{"question": "What is the data source of a Data Warehouse?",
"answers": ["Master Data",
 "Conformed dimension contents from separate repositories",
 "Data Structures based on performance",
 "Historical, atomized data",
 "Staging area"],
"valid": [1]},

{"question": "Why is Data Architecture important to Data Management?",
"answers": ["Provides for an understanding of an organization's data at different levels of abstraction",
 "Creates data about data",
 "Breaks down data systems into easily comprehensible units",
 "Create structured representations of data",
 "Supports the utilization of data to make sound decisions"],
"valid": [0]},

{"question": "Which of the following is NOT a function of Data Architects?",
"answers": ["Facilitate alignment between Business and IT",
 "Act as agents for change, transformation, and agility",
 "Manage complex data and information delivery throughout the enterprise",
 "Translate business needs into data and system requirements so processes will have their required data",
 "Strategize on how to procure data that meets the needs of the organization"],
"valid": [4]},

{"question": "Thomas Redman defines a data item as...",
"answers": ["Representative triple",
 "Representative double",
 "Representable triple",
 "Representable double",
 "Representing triple"],
"valid": [2]},

{"question": "Which of the following is used to exchange information within the Semantic Web?",
"answers": ["Taxonomy",
 "Thesaurus",
 "Data Model",
 "Syntax",
 "Ontology"],
"valid": [4]}
